Something smells good.
Hey, senshi?
There you are.
Oh, you're awake now.
Good morning to you.
I see you made breakfast.
Isn't it great?
Mr. Senshi's an amazing chef.
Yeah, you're right.
Senshi's the best there is.
Mmm.
Mmm, it's so tasty.
Yad.
Huh?
Do you want to try some, too?
But I won't be able to taste it.
Here.
Oh, it's warm.
And it's soft as well.
Your sense of taste is almost like a muscle.
If you don't exercise it regularly, then it gets weak.
So, start building it back up by enjoying textures first.
Got it.
Good.
Stay still.
A very long time ago, I used to dine with my parents and grandfather like this.
Always next to my grandfather was Thistle, who you may know as the Mad Mage.
My great-grandfather first brought him to the castle as a court jester.
I say that the two of them were raised like brothers.
Once my grandfather ascended the throne, Thistle was asked to learn magic and excelled in it.
These lands were originally filled with dwarven and elven artifacts, so there was likely black magic mixed in, too.
Thistle soon became obsessed with power and eventually cast a spell of immortality on us.
Actually, we've been wanting to talk to him.
Do you know where he is right now?
Talk to him?
You're asking for the impossible.
A normal conversation is out of the question.
We went through great trouble to help my grandfather escape.
Those suspected of helping were executed.
But if you just want to meet him, the mage's eyes have started gathering because they've noticed a change here.
The Mad Mage himself will appear before long.
This dungeon is an extension of his arms and legs.
You are aware of his power, aren't you?
We are, but we still need to see him.
I don't know if you'll be able to talk, but go seek help from the winged lion that is imprisoned deep within the dungeon.
He might be able to subdue the mage's power.
You can get inside the castle walls through here, meaning you'll be able to return to the dungeon.
Here you go. Take this with you.
Thanks. You're too kind.
Let's not give them too much. It'll be a huge burden for those carrying them.
What does that mean?
Simply that you'll be leaving this place the same way you came.
Thank you. All of you.
Good luck.
I know I shouldn't say this, but do you really think they're the chosen ones?
I truly wish to think so.
Hey, Yad.
Oh, Thistle.
Tell me, who were you just talking to?
Can we stop falling?
Wait, this is...
Ow, my back.
It's an ancient dwarven cistern.
So it's this whole place, huh? Which part of it are we in?
My compass isn't working.
I guess I should have assumed this would happen, though.
Typical dwarves.
It looks like the remains of a defensive point.
Right?
Does he have traveling sickness?
Probably, since dwarves have sensitive semicircular canals.
Is it the same for gnomes as well?
That, on top of monosickness, I'd assume.
How'd we get here?
Oh, you're back?
Wait, what?
You okay?
Just rest here for a bit.
We're gonna take a look around.
Chill.
Hmm?
You see these symbols on this pillar?
Oh, yeah.
I do see something.
Write down the symbols on the other pillars that are around us.
I can tell roughly where we are that way.
How do you know a thing like that?
These types of places always have some kind of hidden code in them.
Well, I guess in this case,
it just goes to show that not all dwarves have a great sense of direction.
I know where we are.
Looks like we're somewhere in the southeastern part.
Hey!
Guys, we found something!
Oh, that was fast.
We might have found where Fallon is!
You're saying these are Fallon's tracks?
She noticed us getting closer and ran, but...
It was definitely her!
The silhouette said it all!
Right?
It seemed a lot closer to a griffin to me.
Remind me what a griffin is.
Its upper half's a bird, and its lower half is a lion.
There aren't records of this dungeon ever having a griffin.
Is this scent familiar?
They're not dogs, you know.
It reeks a beast.
Either way, we need to catch up to it.
No, we don't.
Huh?
We don't?
But why?
Uh, well, it's just...
It might be Fallon, Senshi.
I...
Um...
Oh, over there.
I've never seen that kind of mushroom before.
Let's cook it.
Seriously?
They look vaguely familiar to me.
That said, I'm pretty sure they're poisonous,
so don't eat them.
I really don't like griffins.
Why are you so scared of a monster you've never even seen?
Whatever, let's just go!
No, please!
Wait a minute!
It's too dangerous out here!
Move!
Whoa, I knew it!
A griffin!
How cool!
It's my first time seeing one!
A griffin?
So I got all worked up for nothing?
Here it comes!
Leave it to me!
Now!
It's too fast!
Senshi!
Don't run away with your back!
Turn to it!
Senshi!
Oh, no.
It happened so fast.
I was useless.
Did anyone see if he had a weapon on him?
He didn't have one.
We have to go find him.
Maybe someone should climb on top of each pillar to look?
He ain't gonna be me, though.
Which way did they go?
We can't do anything if they're somewhere up high.
We won't even find his corpse.
He has no way to defend himself.
Are we really never gonna see him again?
Marcel!
How do we save Senshi?
I'll use a familiar to find him!
You're going to summon a monster?
It's not so much summoning one as it is creating one.
There are three types of summoning.
One, taking control of existing spirits or monsters.
The conditions for it are complicated,
and it's likely the Lord of the Dungeon will notice.
Two, turning plants or animals into monsters.
This one also isn't ideal because you need a lot of prep time.
Three, making them yourself.
That's what I'll be doing.
That one sounds the most difficult.
It is if you're trying to make a fully independent creature,
but for now, we just need it to be able to move at least.
While I prep the magic circle,
can you gather all the meat we have in the pan?
Sure thing.
That's everything?
It'd be nice if you could find a bit more.
There, that's it.
Although we do have some cheese and eggs...
Veggies, too!
Guess it'd still add to the calories.
Bring them!
Right!
What monster are you making?
Is it gonna obey you?
Could you teach me how to...
No!
Go and get yourself certified to handle dangerous magic first!
Wait, is that really a thing?
So, who exactly is that old dwarf guy anyway?
How'd he end up in your party in the first place?
And why is he so obsessed with making food?
Huh?
How do you not know the answer to that?
You all act like you're old buddies!
I mean, I suppose we've never had a chance to ask.
I can relate not wanting to discuss personal matters with people.
Although, I'd be lying if I said I wasn't curious.
There are several things that I'm still hung up on.
Do you remember what he said to us back when we first met him?
It's been a decade since he started researching monster food in this dungeon.
But this dungeon was only discovered six years ago.
That's true.
Also, every single piece of cookware he uses is made from high-quality metal.
He was able to decipher ancient dwarven codes.
He's afraid of a monster from a floor we just reached.
And he always treats me like a child.
Isn't that last one a misunderstanding?
No.
People who don't know about our kind usually jump to that conclusion.
They don't realize that half-foots are another race.
So they assume that we become a tall man or a dwarf when we get older.
However, that only comes from a few regions like the East.
If he's lived here ten years, there's no reason he shouldn't know.
Could it be that Senshi isn't from the surface?
Some time after we rescue him, why don't we ask him to reintroduce himself to us?
Huh?
Is it over now?
It should be.
Let's try to open the lid.
Oh, thank goodness.
I was almost worried I wouldn't succeed.
What's that face?
I said they just needed to move, right?
I couldn't spare the resources to make them aesthetically pleasing, okay?
Now go.
What's wrong?
Its vision is overlapping with my own, and it feels awful.
Can someone put a blindfold on me?
How can the mad mage send out so many of these things and also process their info all at once?
I'm curious.
You can think about that stuff later.
Senshi first.
I'll look for abnormalities based on the dungeon cleaners and spirits around here.
Follow my familiar.
Huh?
Are you not going to be able to keep up?
Do you know how hard it is to walk while flying?
I'm going to carry her.
Would you two mind carrying our bags?
And here we go.
Wait, I'm scared.
Grab around here.
No way!
Are you trying to make me fall?
Stop moving so much!
What the hell is she doing with her arms?
I guess this is what makes her feel safe.
That pillar!
The dungeon cleaners are flocking to it!
That's the place!
Senshi!
There!
Found him!
The griffon trapped him on a pillar up ahead!
I see.
Griffons do that?
We're here to save you, Senshi!
Can you tell it's me?
A fly?
Crap!
How do I get him down?
Just be careful, Marcel.
Griffons have exceptional vision.
It'll already be watching you before you even notice it.
I lost my eyes up there.
Griffons' bodies are very functional.
Their wings are powerful,
and their graceful bodies allow them to adapt quickly.
Plus, their sharp beak and claws,
they're near impossible to avoid.
Creatures are the way they look because of necessity.
They have no need to just be aesthetically pleasing.
Hmm.
Fine, then.
What shape should it take to match up to a griffon?
Hmm.
You sure that horn is necessary?
This shape will make it a lot more aerodynamic.
So now it'll be able to move much quicker.
Do you remember the wyverns that the mad mage had patrolling?
They were as fast as an arrow.
Let's try to aim for that shape.
Send it out like this and see the difference it makes.
It moves so fast now!
I think this'll work!
Until Senshi's back on the ground,
I'll try to distract the griffon!
Everyone else cover me and prepare for battle!
Why is she flapping?
Maybe it gives her a sense of unity.
All right, Senshi.
Grab onto this rope!
Now, the next move is...
So fast!
I have to lead it away!
Come on!
Over here!
Just get to the ground and...
It got me again.
This is bad.
I can't even compete with it.
What do I do?
You can leave everything to me!
I've got this!
I'll make it way stronger!
I'll put more horns here,
arrange the fangs,
equip it with sharp claws,
add some scales,
and...
Give it two heads!
Now all of its strength and abilities are doubled!
It breathes fire and ice!
So cool!
How can it win a fight against a griffon?
Does it need more attack?
Or more defense?
No!
It doesn't need claws or fangs!
Something fast, elegant, and beautiful!
What I need is the resolution and ego
to create a creature made solely to save Senshi!
It was in that moment
that all of Marcil's thoughts
and her prayers
manifested into a miracle.
I shall bestow you with a name!
Silver wings that will soar the heavens!
I summon thee...
Skyfish!
So...
stupid.
Shut up!
It's fine!
Now then,
time to fly!
So fast!
You move so creepily!
I'm going all out!
Everyone, prepare for battle!
What the hell is she doing now?
Her best!
Or something close.
Yeah!
Whoa!
It's hard to control this thing!
All right!
Now this time...
I'll turn around and...
pierce through!
Are you hurt?
I'm fine.
We should probably take a good rest.
You go relax over there, Senshi.
While I do the cooking.
Huh?
Thank you.
Rest in peace,
my Skyfish.
Whoa!
This is actually pretty cool.
Vegetables are packed in there like organs.
Did you need it for something?
No, not really, but...
I just, you know,
was hoping to have a little more time to mourn,
and now I can't.
Are you okay, Senshi?
I don't know.
It's fine.
Do whatever.
Chop up the summon creature into the desired length.
Trim off the wings at the base.
Squeeze out all the moisture with a scrap of cloth.
Salt and pepper.
Take the wings and roll them.
Dunk each piece of meat you chopped earlier
into a mixture of flour, egg, and water.
Then fry.
For the wings,
quickly dip them in oil to cook them.
Serve with a sauce,
and it's ready.
This is seriously the perfect fusion of meat and veggies.
If you say so.
You think summoning spells could play a big part in the art of cooking?
I sure hope not,
considering you need to sacrifice a week's worth of ingredients.
Damn it.
I knew I should have brought some of that ale with me.
Make sure you eat more than just the wings, Izutsumi.
Nuh-uh.
Have a bite, Senshi.
Worried about the griffon?
We're draining its blood help?
Maybe.
No, that's not it.
I-I'm just not all that hungry at the moment.
Hey, uh, Senshi.
My name is Chilchuk.
I was born in a small village
found in a basin to the northeast.
Since about ten years ago,
I've been doing odd jobs in various dungeons.
Piclocking, translation,
even being the middleman.
Also,
I have a wife and kids,
but for reasons I haven't seen them in a while.
Uh!
A wife and kids?
Well, that about sums it up for my backstory.
You mind telling us some stuff about you?
How'd you end up living in this dungeon?
Did something happen?
Hmm.
My name is Senshi of Izganda.
I used to be a member of a small mining group.
And while I say a mining group,
we weren't actually looking to collect ore.
What we were really after
were ruins that stood before the war,
hoping to strike it rich.
But ore is most of what we dug up each day, of course.
If we were lucky,
we would come across a few relics
like cogwheels and lenses
every once in a while.
Then one day,
after some usual digging,
we dug our way to something huge.
Oh.
An ancient castle,
brilliantly shining with gold.
That's right.
It was this very dungeon.